{
    "id": "f2be1b1bb50446da9dd8619300fca171",
    "title": "Direct And Indirect Speech Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Ramesh said that he ....................... his homework.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "finished",
                "has finished",
                "had finished"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The boy asked his mother ....................... he could watch TV.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "if",
                "that",
                "weather"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The man asked the passerby if he ....................... help him.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "would",
                "can"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The girl said that I ........................ on her seat.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "am sitting",
                "was sitting",
                "have been sitting"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The man asked the boy where ........................",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "was he going",
                "he was going",
                "was going he"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The girl asked who ......................... her pen.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "have taken",
                "had taken",
                "would take"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The teacher advised the students ..................... hard.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "to work",
                "working",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The mother told the boy ..................... there.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "to wait",
                "waiting",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The manager asked the clerk ........................... that file to the secretary.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "to take",
                "taking",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The old man asked me if I ...................... help him.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "would",
                "can"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Ramesh said that he ...................... John the previous day.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "have seen",
                "had seen",
                "would see"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}